<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on संस्कृतजालक्षेत्रम्</title>
    <link>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on संस्कृतजालक्षेत्रम्</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1910 sikh argentina</title>
      <link>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/1910-sikh-argentina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/1910-sikh-argentina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://scroll.in/magazine/1088915/when-sikhs-chased-a-new-world-in-argentina-and-found-a-nightmare-instead&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the early 1900s, Argentina was among the wealthiest countries in the western hemisphere. Its economy was booming and, fuelled by foreign investment, its vast, fertile lands had made it a major exporter of livestock and agricultural produce. New industries sprang up, creating a demand for labour that European migrants alone could not meet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;advertisement&#34;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Noticing how Indian workers were employed across the Caribbean, the authorities in Buenos Aires approached their representative in India to explore the possibility of encouraging migration from the subcontinent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1920s cuba discouragement</title>
      <link>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/1920s-cuba-discouragement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/1920s-cuba-discouragement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;liverpool&#34;&gt;Liverpool&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On a summer morning in 1926, twelve exhausted Indian men disembarked from the &lt;em&gt;SS Croya&lt;/em&gt; at the British port of Liverpool. They had boarded the steamship in Cuba, disillusioned by their life on the Caribbean island.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As subjects of the British Empire, they had the legal right to reside in Britain, but their intention was to return to India as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“They planted themselves on the landing stage and upon being approached by the police explained they hoped to be able to work their way home on a boat to India from Liverpool,”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1970s proposal</title>
      <link>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/1970s-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/1970s-proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Send millions of Indian peasants to Brazil to eradicate poverty and starvation’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the mid-1970s, an association in Kerala made this unorthodox proposal to the Indian government, reviving an idea whose roots go back further.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ajay Kamalakaran&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Send millions of Indian peasants to Brazil to eradicate poverty and starvation’&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In February 1974, Indian President VV Giri and Prime Minister Indira Gandhi received a letter from Kerala with an unexpected request: “promoting a mass emigration of Indian peasants” to Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argentine rural land law faq</title>
      <link>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/argentine-rural-land-law-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/argentine-rural-land-law-faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are rural lands?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rural lands are all those that are outside urban areas, regardless of the destination that is given to them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreign-people&#34;&gt;Foreign people&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can foreigners buy rural land in Argentina?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, but the law prohibits foreigners from owning or possessing:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lands with important and permanent bodies of water or that border important and permanent bodies of water.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Land located in border security zones.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there a limit to the total amount of rural land that foreigners can have?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rjrasva list</title>
      <link>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/rjrasva-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sanskrit.github.io/groups/dyuganga/projects/schools/lat-am-settlement/articles/rjrasva-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Rjrasva/status/1760411201614295295&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natural resources: Latin America &amp;gt; overexploited old-world countries by far whether it be empty land, minerals, water, oil &amp;amp; gas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ease of entry: Generally Latin America has easy path to entry, residency, &amp;amp; citizenship including jus soli (birth right citizenship)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quality of life: Much better than India whether it be traffic, pollution, honking, cleanliness&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pay: Higher wages than India, in some cases much higher as in the case of Chile Uruguay&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chances of backlash: Lower because there is no 1 set apart founding ethnic group that feels threatened by immigrants. Most Latinos are Mestizo&amp;rsquo;s who sometimes are hard to tell apart from Indians from India. Catholicism is also collapsing throughout Latin America with rise of secularism + evangelicals, so becoming religiously diverse as well&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;MERCOSUR, Andean Community, Pacific Alliance all means ease of movement from 1 Latin American country to another&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Existing old Hindu diasporas in Suriname, Guyana, &amp;amp; Trinidad &amp;amp; Tobago. In the case of Suriname they have even retained Sarnami Hindi after 150 years&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Geopolitical stability: No major wars between Latin American countries in living memory, is covered by US Monroe doctrine&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Crime &amp;amp; cartels: Issues in some but not others. Chile, Uruguay, Paraguay, Panama, Peru, Costa Rica, Argentina don&amp;rsquo;t have cartels &amp;amp; gangs running amok.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vvs-aiyar-attempt&#34;&gt;VVS Aiyar attempt&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.srimatham.com/uploads/5/5/4/9/5549439/kamba.pdf&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
